Now the S and P
itself. Friday's video said the
constructive read survives only above
seventy-five oh-four. Monday was the
second straight settle below it
— seventy-four forty-three, with the
session low at seventy-four forty,
about nineteen points above the
July low at seventy-four twenty-two.
Nineteen points, give or take.
That's the entire cushion between
"pullback inside an uptrend" and
"the July range is broken."
Breadth agreed with the sellers
— the Dow gave up
six tenths, three hundred seven
points, the worst of the
three averages. And the top
of the structure hasn't moved:
the July high at seventy-five
eighty-one, printed July fifteenth, sits
untouched above all of this.
The index is still only
about one point eight percent
off its July high, so
nobody serious is calling this
a crash — but an
index losing its line while