Monday gave you the whole
story in one bar. The
S and P opened up
four tenths of a percent,
tried to shake off Friday's
war scare, got as far
as seventy-five thirteen — and
sellers ran it all the
way back down: seventy-four forty-three
at the bell, down two
tenths, within three points of
the day's low. Oil told
the rest of it: Brent
touched ninety-one on the ninth
day of American strikes on
Iran, then gave almost all
of it back by the
settle. And the bounce still
failed anyway. My read: the
pressure has moved from oil
to rates. The ten-year climbed
to four point five nine,
a few basis points off
its July high, and that's
the number doing the squeezing.
Tonight I'll prove it chart
by chart, and I'll leave
you with the two numbers
that decide Tuesday.
Start with the record, because