Monday gave you the whole
story in one bar. The
S and P opened up
four tenths of a percent,
tried to shake off Friday's
war scare, got as far
as seventy-five thirteen — and
sellers ran it all the
way back down: seventy-four forty-three
at the bell, down two
tenths, within three points of
the day's low. Oil told
the rest of it: Brent
touched ninety-one on the ninth
day of American strikes on
Iran, then gave almost all
of it back by the
settle. And the bounce still
failed anyway. My read: the
pressure has moved from oil
to rates. The ten-year climbed
to four point five nine,
a few basis points off
its July high, and that's
the number doing the squeezing.
Tonight I'll prove it chart
by chart, and I'll leave
you with the two numbers
that decide Tuesday.
Start with the record, because
the weekend redrew the board.
Yemen's Houthis declared a naval
blockade against Saudi Arabia on
Monday — Reuters broke it
in the morning — aimed
at the Red Sea route
the Saudis have been using
to move barrels around the
blocked strait. NBC News puts
that workaround near four and
a half million barrels a
day out of Yanbu. Read
the declaration again: the workaround
is now the target. When
the detour itself gets blockaded,
the market has to price
the whole region.
And the strikes themselves hit
day nine. N P R
has the shape of the
weekend: nine straight days of
American bombing since the peace
talks collapsed over the Strait
of Hormuz memorandum, and a
third American service member killed
in operations since Friday. Central
Command says the newest wave
targets Iran's ability to hit
commercial shipping. Iran answered in
kind — N P R
counts a strike near the
American position at Al-Tanf in
Syria and drone attacks on
two bases in Kuwait, the
second straight day Kuwaiti infrastructure
took fire. The President said
Iran, quote, will pay. So
both oil routes out of
the Gulf are contested at
once, the retaliation is widening,
and that's the backdrop every
chart tonight sits on.
Brent's daily bar shows you
exactly where the war premium
stands. It opened at eighty-nine
thirty, ran to ninety-one forty-two
— a new July high
— traded as low as
eighty-six twelve, and settled at
eighty-eight eighty, up just six
tenths on the day. That's
better than a five-dollar range
inside one session. Now the
levels. Eighty-seven fifty-five was the
spike high from the week
the strait first shut —
nothing closed above it for
a month, and now Friday
and Monday have both settled
above it, so the old
ceiling is acting like a
shelf. Above, Monday's rejection at
ninety-one forty-two is the line
the bulls have to reclaim.
For context on the run
into Monday: Friday alone jumped
four percent off Thursday's close
at eighty-four eighty-five — Monday's
stall came at the end
of that run. CNBC puts
crude up roughly twenty percent
for July. For scale on
why this matters beyond the
pump: before the war, the
E I A counted about
a fifth of the world's
petroleum liquids moving through Hormuz
every day, and first-quarter flow
already ran close to thirty
percent below last year. The
premium is real. Monday just
showed you it needs fresh
escalation to grow.
Energy stocks held the move
better than crude did. X
L E closed at fifty-seven
ninety-four, up about half a
percent on a red tape,
after printing fifty-eight thirty-nine —
a new July high. Friday's
video named fifty-seven thirty as
the breakout trigger, and the
fund has now closed above
it two sessions in a
row. That's what a real
breakout looks like: old resistance
got tested from above and
held, twice. The line in
the sand is unchanged. Hold
above fifty-seven thirty on the
retest and energy stays the
leadership sector. Slip back under
it and the whole move
gets reclassified as premium that
leaked into equities and leaked
right back out.
Drill one level down, because
the sector fund is being
carried by its heavyweights. Exxon
closed at one forty-eight thirty-six,
up about seven tenths, after
tagging one forty-nine on the
day. The July ceiling sits
at one fifty even —
Friday's tag — and Exxon
has now spent two sessions
knocking on it. A daily
close through one fifty puts
the biggest name in the
fund at new July highs
with a war calendar behind
it. Chevron is a step
ahead. It closed at one
eighty-nine seventy-one, up one and
a quarter percent, and printed
one ninety thirty-five — a
fresh July high, on a
day the broad market closed
red. When the number-two name
in the sector makes new
monthly highs on a red
tape, that's real buying, and
it's the strongest evidence on
the board that the energy
rotation has money behind it.
Strength like that in the
oil names only holds if
the bond market confirms the
inflation story. Monday it did.
The ten-year Treasury yield rose
four and a half basis
points on Monday and settled
at four point five nine
— session high a touch
above four point six —
a few basis points under
the July high at four
point six four. My read
starts with what didn't happen
there. On a day with
a blockade headline and American
casualties, money did not hide
in Treasuries. Yields went up.
That's the oil-to-inflation channel doing
exactly what the textbook says:
a twenty percent crude move
feeds inflation expectations, inflation expectations
keep the Fed careful, and
the discount rate on every
long-duration asset creeps higher. Gold
settled flat at four thousand
seven — no haven bid
at all, on exactly the
kind of day that usually
produces one. Put those together
and you get an orderly
repricing, driven by the rates
math more than the headlines.
Now watch what that rate
pressure did to tech. The
Nasdaq one hundred opened up
nearly one percent at twenty-eight
eight seventy-one, tagged twenty-nine thousand
seventeen, and then spent the
whole session giving every point
of it back — closed
twenty-eight six oh-four, flat on
the day. The level story
is uglier than the flat
close. Twenty-eight eight fourteen was
the July floor that held
twice; the index has now
settled below it two sessions
running, so old support is
now overhead resistance. Underneath, Friday's
low at twenty-eight two thirty-one
is the July low and
the last defense before the
June range, which tops out
near twenty-eight two hundred —
very little shelf between Friday's
low and the round twenty-eight
thousand. Monday's low was twenty-eight
five ninety — it never
tested Friday's low, so the
selling stayed orderly. An index
that can't hold a one-percent
gap on good overnight footing
is an index where the
marginal buyer has stepped away.
Now the S and P
itself. Friday's video said the
constructive read survives only above
seventy-five oh-four. Monday was the
second straight settle below it
— seventy-four forty-three, with the
session low at seventy-four forty,
about nineteen points above the
July low at seventy-four twenty-two.
Nineteen points, give or take.
That's the entire cushion between
"pullback inside an uptrend" and
"the July range is broken."
Breadth agreed with the sellers
— the Dow gave up
six tenths, three hundred seven
points, the worst of the
three averages. And the top
of the structure hasn't moved:
the July high at seventy-five
eighty-one, printed July fifteenth, sits
untouched above all of this.
The index is still only
about one point eight percent
off its July high, so
nobody serious is calling this
a crash — but an
index losing its line while
yields press their July high
is how orderly pullbacks become
trends.
The VIX barely moved Monday,
and that's the story. It
closed at eighteen sixty-six —
off a tenth on the
day, but sitting in the
top quarter of its July
range after Friday's jump from
the sixteens. It didn't spike
on the blockade headline and
it didn't bleed back to
fifteen either. For the frame:
the July floor is just
under fifteen, Thursday closed sixteen
seventy-two, and the July top
at nineteen fifty printed Friday.
Monday parked between them, closer
to the top. The options
market has settled into a
new, higher resting heart rate
into the biggest earnings week
of the month. It's carrying
the war as a standing
risk and charging a standing
price for it.
One honest correction to Friday's
map before I redraw it:
seventy-five oh-four broke, but yields
never broke lower. The selling
repriced inflation; money never ran
to safety. So here's the
new map, starting with the
index. Base case is the
squeeze: the S and P
boxed between seventy-four twenty-two and
seventy-five oh-four into Wednesday's earnings.
Losing seventy-four twenty-two on a
settle opens the June range
below. Reclaiming seventy-five oh-four retires
the whole bearish read. For
scale, JPMorgan's official year-end target
sits at seventy-two hundred —
the big desks were braced
for lower well before this
week. Crude's side of the
map: base case keeps Brent
boxed between eighty-seven fifty-five and
ninety-one forty-two while the diplomacy
question hangs. Escalation is a
settle above ninety-one forty-two —
and if the disruption persists
at that scale, Goldman's April
scenario work sketched Brent north
of one hundred; that's the
outer edge of the map,
and I'm not forecasting it.
De-escalation runs the other way:
renewed diplomatic contact is the
trigger, and the confirmation is
a settle back under eighty-seven
fifty-five — that's when the
week's premium starts coming out.
Rates arbitrate all of it:
the ten-year clearing four point
six four confirms the inflation
premium and re-prices every equity
chart in this video, while
holding under it keeps the
squeeze orderly. And energy tells
you whether the rotation is
real. The fifty-seven thirty retest
holding says the rotation is
real money. A slip back
under it says the whole
move was war premium passing
through — and I'll call
it that way if it
prints.
The calendar decides which way
this breaks. Wednesday after the
close: Alphabet and Tesla, the
first of the megacap prints,
with Alphabet's capital spending as
the A I signal everyone
actually cares about — plus
I B M's full call,
five o'clock Eastern, after its
preliminary release cost the stock
twenty-five percent in a day,
the worst day it has
ever printed. The same week
brings Intel, General Motors, Lockheed
Martin, and A M D.
The calendar gives you jobless
claims Thursday and the July
flash P M I s
Friday. And the Fed is
in blackout until the decision
on July twenty-ninth, so the
bond market has no speeches
to trade against — only
the oil chart.
Quick recap so you walk
into Tuesday ready. Both Gulf
oil routes are contested. Brent
needs ninety-one forty-two back to
prove the premium is growing;
eighty-seven fifty-five is the shelf
underneath. Energy is the breakout
that stuck, as long as
fifty-seven thirty holds. The Nasdaq's
old floor at twenty-eight eight
fourteen is now its lid,
and Friday's low at twenty-eight
two thirty-one is the last
defense. The S and P
sits about nineteen points above
the July low at seventy-four
twenty-two. And the ten-year at
four point six four is
the line that turns a
pullback into a trend. If
you only keep two numbers
for Tuesday, keep those: seventy-four
twenty-two on the S and
P, four point six four
on the ten-year. The completed
bars will answer, same as
always, and I'll walk you
through whichever answer prints. If
a desk that talks in
settled levels instead of headlines
is useful to you, subscribe
— it's one click, and
it keeps this thing daily.
See you after the close.