Yesterday's map gave you two
triggers, and Tuesday hit them
both. Reclaiming seventy-five oh-four retires
the bearish read — that
was the line, and the
S and P closed at
seventy-five oh-nine, first settle back
above the wall since it
broke. The trade that did
the lifting was memory chips:
Micron gapped up seven percent
at the open and finished
up twelve, the loudest single-name
move on the board. And
the other trigger printed on
the other side of the
tape — Brent settled at
ninety-one sixty-three, through Monday's rejection
high at ninety-one forty-two, the
level I said the bulls
had to reclaim to prove
the war premium is still
growing. They reclaimed it in
one session. So stocks called
off the alarm on the
same day oil raised it,
and the ten-year closed a
basis point under its July
high while all of that
happened. Somebody's read on this
war is wrong, and tonight