Micron's daily bar is what
conviction looks like. The stock
closed Monday at eight sixty-five
and change, opened Tuesday at
nine twenty-five — a seven
percent gap before the first
trade — ran as high
as nine eighty-two eighty-eight, and
settled at nine seventy, up
twelve percent on the day.
A gap that holds all
session means buyers never let
the stock trade back into
Monday's range. The level framework
is clean: Monday's high sat
at nine oh-one, and the
gap cleared it at the
open — that's the floor
the bulls have to defend
now, because a close back
under nine oh-one fills the
gap and unwinds the whole
statement. Above, today's high at
nine eighty-two is the ceiling
the next leg has to
take. The mechanism matters more
than the candle: memory pricing
is where A I demand
shows up first — chips
get ordered before data centers
get built — so when