Yesterday's map gave you two
triggers, and Tuesday hit them
both. Reclaiming seventy-five oh-four retires
the bearish read — that
was the line, and the
S and P closed at
seventy-five oh-nine, first settle back
above the wall since it
broke. The trade that did
the lifting was memory chips:
Micron gapped up seven percent
at the open and finished
up twelve, the loudest single-name
move on the board. And
the other trigger printed on
the other side of the
tape — Brent settled at
ninety-one sixty-three, through Monday's rejection
high at ninety-one forty-two, the
level I said the bulls
had to reclaim to prove
the war premium is still
growing. They reclaimed it in
one session. So stocks called
off the alarm on the
same day oil raised it,
and the ten-year closed a
basis point under its July
high while all of that
happened. Somebody's read on this
war is wrong, and tonight
I'll walk you through both
sides of the argument, chart
by chart, and leave you
the numbers that settle it.
Start with the index bar,
because the shape matters as
much as the close. The
S and P opened at
seventy-four ninety — still under
the wall — worked through
seventy-five oh-four, printed seventy-five fifteen
at the high, and settled
at seventy-five oh-nine, up nine
tenths of a percent. That
snapped a three-day losing streak.
Now the honest size of
the win: five points of
daylight above the level, on
one close. Monday's tape got
above this same line intraday
and sellers ran it back
seventy points by the bell;
Tuesday's buyers took it and
kept it, and the difference
between those sessions is the
whole argument for the bounce.
The bar I want next
is the retest. Old ceilings
get respected from above or
they get given back fast,
and seventy-five oh-four is now
the floor that grades every
session this week. Below it,
Tuesday's low at seventy-four sixty-eight
is the deeper line —
lose both and this close
goes back in the failed-bounce
file next to Monday's.
Here's what actually paid for
the rally. The Motley Fool's
market wrap has the roster:
Micron surged twelve percent, Sandisk
soared fourteen, and A M
D added eight percent, extending
its run on the artificial
intelligence deal with Microsoft. The
fuel was strong export data
out of South Korea —
the memory-supply capital of the
world — which the Fool
reads as evidence that A
I demand hasn't cooled. Their
line on the tape: today's
gains offer some reassurance that
the recent pullback was more
of a reset rather than
a wider loss of confidence.
The filings backed it up
as well: Nvidia disclosed a
nine point three percent stake
in Nebius, the A I
cloud builder it first backed
with two billion dollars last
year — that's a balance
sheet talking, and it says
the biggest chip company on
earth still wants more compute
capacity, not less. And the
same wrap flags tomorrow's results
from Alphabet and Tesla as
the next read on whether
the spending holds. Hold that
thought — it anchors the
calendar at the end.
Micron's daily bar is what
conviction looks like. The stock
closed Monday at eight sixty-five
and change, opened Tuesday at
nine twenty-five — a seven
percent gap before the first
trade — ran as high
as nine eighty-two eighty-eight, and
settled at nine seventy, up
twelve percent on the day.
A gap that holds all
session means buyers never let
the stock trade back into
Monday's range. The level framework
is clean: Monday's high sat
at nine oh-one, and the
gap cleared it at the
open — that's the floor
the bulls have to defend
now, because a close back
under nine oh-one fills the
gap and unwinds the whole
statement. Above, today's high at
nine eighty-two is the ceiling
the next leg has to
take. The mechanism matters more
than the candle: memory pricing
is where A I demand
shows up first — chips
get ordered before data centers
get built — so when
the memory names lead, the
market is trading the supply
chain's earliest signal.
Now the other war story,
the one the equity tape
looked straight through. Reuters, carried
on B N N Bloomberg,
has Tuesday's record: American forces
bombed targets in southern Iran
overnight after the President said
Tehran would pay dearly for
the deaths of American soldiers,
and Iran answered by striking
American sites in Bahrain, Kuwait,
and Jordan. In the strait
itself, a tanker was hit
by a projectile and its
crew abandoned ship. Yemen's Houthis
threatened a naval blockade of
Saudi Arabia, and two Saudi
tankers have already reversed course
in the Red Sea. Mediators
are floating a ten-day ceasefire;
nobody has taken it. U
B S analyst Giovanni Staunovo's
read, quote: lower exports through
the Strait of Hormuz and
concerns of potential supply disruption
from oil coming through the
Red Sea are moderately supporting
oil prices. Day ten, both
routes contested, and the ceasefire
is an offer on a
table nobody is sitting at.
Brent priced that record honestly.
The bar: opened at eighty-eight
ninety-five, ran to ninety-one ninety-nine,
held eighty-seven eighty-seven at the
low, and settled at ninety-one
sixty-three — up three point
two percent, and through the
ninety-one forty-two rejection high that
capped Monday. Yahoo Finance flags
it as oil's highest level
since mid-June. Remember the sequence
here: Monday tagged ninety-one forty-two
and gave nearly all of
it back — that was
the premium stalling. Tuesday took
the same level out and
closed above it. The shelf
structure moves up accordingly: ninety-one
forty-two is now the first
support — the old rejection
working as the new floor
— and today's high at
ninety-one ninety-nine is the line
that opens the June spike
range if it goes. A
premium that closes at its
highest since mid-June while a
ceasefire offer sits ignored on
the table is a market
telling you what it thinks
of the offer.
The producers signed off on
it, which is the part
I always check before trusting
an oil move. X L
E closed at fifty-eight fifty,
up about one percent, and
printed fifty-eight fifty-three at the
high. The old July ceiling
at fifty-eight thirty-nine — Monday's
rejection high — was taken
out and held into the
bell. The staircase underneath is
intact: fifty-seven thirty was the
original breakout trigger from Friday's
map, the fund has now
closed above it three sessions
running, and each ceiling it
clears keeps turning into the
next shelf. Crude up three
percent with the sector fund
at July-high closes is a
supply premium with money behind
it — the barrels and
the equity are pricing the
same story. If they ever
split, that split becomes the
lead of this show. They
haven't.
The bond market split the
difference between the stories. The
ten-year yield rose three basis
points and settled at four
point six three, after running
to four point six four
intraday — right into the
July high, the line yesterday's
map named as the trigger
that re-prices everything else. It
got touched and it held,
barely. Read the mechanism: crude
at its highest since mid-June
feeds energy inflation, inflation keeps
the Fed careful, and the
discount rate on every long-duration
asset creeps up. That channel
is live — yields pressed
their ceiling on a day
stocks rallied, which means money
was not hiding in Treasuries
either. And here's the tension
I can't resolve for you
tonight: the most rate-sensitive index
on the board led the
market higher while the ten-year
sat on its July high.
That divergence has to resolve.
The Fed is silent until
the decision on July twenty-ninth
— blackout — so between
now and then, the resolution
comes from the oil chart
or the earnings tape, nowhere
else.
Look at the leader with
that tension in mind. The
Nasdaq one hundred opened at
twenty-nine thousand fifty-nine, ran to
twenty-nine one ninety-two, and settled
at twenty-nine one fifty-five —
up just under two percent,
the strongest of the majors.
The level work: twenty-eight eight
fourteen, the July floor that
turned into a lid last
week, flipped back under the
index in one session —
Tuesday's low at twenty-eight eight
ninety-one never even tested it.
That lid had held as
resistance for two straight sessions,
and clearing it is the
tech tape's way of saying
the pullback ran out of
sellers. The ceiling above is
Tuesday's high at twenty-nine one
ninety-two, with the July high
above that. But hold the
divergence: duration-heavy tech rallying two
percent into a ten-year parked
at its July high is
the market betting that A
I earnings power beats the
rates math. Alphabet and Tesla
report tomorrow night, and that
bet gets marked to market
immediately.
The VIX closed at seventeen
oh-four, down nearly nine percent,
with a session low at
sixteen eighty-six. Tuesday unwound nearly
all of the risk premium
the options market spent Friday
and Monday building — Friday's
jump, Monday's standing price at
eighteen sixty-six, most of it
handed back in an afternoon.
The frame: nineteen fifty is
the July top, printed Friday;
sixteen eighty-six is Tuesday's low,
with the July floor just
under fifteen beneath it. An
options market at seventeen with
a tanker abandoned in Hormuz
that morning is a market
that has decided the war
stays contained to shipping lanes
and out of the earnings
tape. Maybe it's right —
it was right to look
through the last escalation. But
that's now a crowded, cheap-insurance
bet, and nineteen fifty is
the number that says it's
unwinding.
One more story from Tuesday,
because it's the rule for
the next two weeks of
earnings. Danaher beat on both
lines — a dollar ninety-four
adjusted against a dollar eighty-three
expected, six point two seven
billion in revenue, up five
and a half percent —
and the stock still tanked
fourteen percent, the worst decliner
in the S and P,
because the company cut its
twenty twenty-six core growth outlook
to three-to-four percent from three-to-six
and guided the third quarter
to just two-to-three. Benzinga's earnings
desk has the detail: bioprocessing
orders actually grew mid-teens, but
the outlook came down anyway.
Same session, other direction: 3M
beat with two dollars forty
in adjusted earnings on six
and a half billion in
revenue and raised its full-year
guide to a range of
eight eighty to eight ninety-five,
from eight fifty to eight
seventy. General Motors raised its
full-year operating profit guide for
the second time this year,
to fourteen-to-sixteen billion, while absorbing
an assumed two and a
half to three and a
half billion in tariff costs.
The pattern across the tape:
the quarter you just printed
is table stakes. The guide
is the product. Sellers paid
fourteen percent to teach that
lesson once on Tuesday —
watch what the next thin
guide costs.
So here's the map with
both triggers spent. The index
side: base case is that
the breakout gets its retest
— seventy-five oh-four holds on
a settle basis and the
S and P grades higher
into the megacap prints, with
Tuesday's low at seventy-four sixty-eight
as the deeper floor. Give
the level back on a
settle and the whole week
reverts to Monday's squeeze between
seventy-four twenty-two and seventy-five oh-four.
The oil side: base case
keeps Brent shelved above ninety-one
forty-two while the ceasefire offer
hangs. Escalation is a settle
through ninety-one ninety-nine — that
reopens the June spike range
above. De-escalation has a named
trigger for once — the
ten-day ceasefire actually landing —
and the confirmation is a
settle back under ninety-one forty-two,
which starts refunding the week's
premium. If that refund starts,
X L E giving back
fifty-eight thirty-nine confirms it from
the equity side. Rates arbitrate
the whole board, same as
yesterday: the ten-year clearing four
point six four on a
settle confirms the inflation transmission
and taxes every equity chart
in this video, and holding
under it keeps Tuesday's bet
alive. The calendar does the
rest: Alphabet and Tesla after
Wednesday's close — the A
I spending read that either
feeds Micron's tape or starves
it — and the Fed
decision lands July twenty-ninth with
no speeches in between. If
you keep two numbers, keep
ninety-one forty-two on Brent and
four point six four on
the ten-year: the first says
whether the war premium keeps
building, the second says when
it starts costing the stock
market. The completed bars will
answer, same as always, and
I'll walk you through whichever
answer prints. If a desk
that talks in settled levels
instead of headlines is useful
to you, subscribe — one
click, and it keeps this
thing daily. See you after
the close.